(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-23T01:29:11.656096",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
だって僕は星だから
Because I am a star,
照らせ 照らせ
Shine, shine!
きっと君はもう気付いていた
I'm sure you had already noticed
僕の心の奥で描いた
what was drawn deep inside my heart.
それがこれから話す陳腐なモノローグさ
That is the cliché monologue I'm about to tell.
ずっと言えない言葉があった
There were words I could never say,
壊せない壁があったんだ
walls that could never be broken down.
ふっと香り立つ朝の匂いが
Suddenly, the scent of morning wafting in
どうしようもなく憎々しくて
felt so unbearably hateful,
部屋の隅で膝を抱えて震えていた
that I sat in the corner of the room, hugging my knees and trembling.
太陽なんていらないから
I don't need any sun,
明けないでいて
so please don't let dawn come.
その手を伸ばして
Reach out your hand
誰かに届くように
so that it reaches someone.
僕だって君と同じ
I'm just like you,
特別なんじゃないから
neither of us is special,
そうさ僕は夜を歌うよ
so I will sing through the night,
stellar stellar
ありったけの輝きで
With all the brilliance I have,
今宵音楽はずっとずっと止まらない
tonight, the music will never, ever stop.
そうだ僕がずっとなりたかったのは待ってるシンデレラじゃないさ
That's right, what I always wanted to become wasn't a waiting Cinderella,
迎えに行く王子様だ
but the prince going to rescue her.
だって僕は星だから
Because I am a star.
なんてありふれた話なんだ
What a cliché story that is,
ノートの隅に眠る本物のワンシーンだ
a genuine scene sleeping in the corner of a notebook.
きっとあの星も泣いてるんだ
I'm sure that star is crying too,
明日なんて来ないままでいて
so stay without tomorrow ever coming.
その手を伸ばして
Reach out your hand
誰かに届くように
so that it reaches someone.
本当に大切なものは目に見えないようなものなんだ
What's truly precious is something invisible to the eye,
そうさ僕は夜を歌うよ
so I will sing through the night,
stellar stellar
だって 僕は星だから stellar stellar
Just like the shooting star I am, stellar stellar
きっと君はもう気づいていた
I'm sure you'd already noticed it
ぼくの心の奥で描いた
What I drew deep within my heart
それがこれから話す陳腐なモノローグさ
Is the cliché monologue I'll tell from now on
ずっと言えない言葉があった
There were words I could never say
壊せない壁があったんだ ずっとさ
There was a wall that couldn't be broken, always
ふっと香り立つ朝の匂いが
The scent of morning drifting softly
どうしようもなく憎らしくて
Was hopelessly hateful to me
部屋の隅で膝を抱えて震えていていた
Cuddling my knees in the corner of the room, trembling
太陽なんていらないから
I don't need the sun
明けないでいて
Please don't let dawn break
その手を伸ばして 誰かに届くように
Reach out your hand so it reaches someone
ぼくだって君と同じ特別なんかじゃないから
Because I'm not special, just like you
そうさ 僕は夜を歌うよ stellar stellar
That's right, I sing to the night, stellar stellar
ありったけの輝きで 今宵 音楽はきっときっと止まらない
With all my brilliance, tonight music will surely never stop
そうだ 僕がずっとなりたかったのは 待ってるシンデレラじゃないさ
What I always wanted to be wasn't a waiting Cinderella
迎えに行く王子様だ だって 僕は星だから
But the prince going to greet her, because I am a star!
そうだ 僕は星だから stellar stellar
That's right, I am a star, stellar stellar
そうだ 僕は星だから
That's right, because I am a star
stellar stellar...
はーい！ということで皆さんお疲れ様です！
Hii! And so everyone, great work!
声がね、声がね、久しぶりの！
My voice is... it's been a while!
すいちゃんの声、空いてるVTuberは、そう、
Suichan's voice—vtubers taking a break, right,
すいちゃんは今日も可愛い！いー！うわー！
Suichan is cute today too! Yay! Wow!
お久しぶりだな！
Long time no see, everyone!
えー、声帯の手術をしてまいりまして、一ヶ月半お休みをいただき、
I underwent vocal cord surgery and took a month and a half off,
えー、こんなふうに、えー、元に戻りました！無事に元に戻りました！
and um, like this, uh, I'm back to normal! Safely back to normal!
どうですか皆さん、すいちゃんの声に変化はありますか？ありませんか？
What do you think, everyone? Is there any change in Suichan's voice?
コメントを打ってくださってる皆さんもね、スパチャを送ってくださってる皆さんも、ありがとうございます！
Thank you to everyone commenting and sending super chats! Please subscribe!
ということで、本日は重大告知を引っさげて復帰をさせていただくということでね、最後まで見ていただいてよろしくお願いいたします！
So today, we're returning with a major announcement! Please watch till the end!
それでは、次の曲に早速行きたいと思います！バイバ～イ！
Well then, let's move right along to the next song! Bye-bye!
画面の向こうの そのまた向こうで
On the other side of the screen, and even beyond that,
放たれた言葉たち
the words that were cast out
殴っても痛くない 透明な拳
Transparent fists that don't hurt when you strike
満天の星のように 散らばっている
Scattered like stars across the night sky
ガラスの破片の上を
Like walking barefoot
裸足で歩くような痛みだ
on shards of glass—such pain.
僕はずっと苦しかったんだ
I've been suffering for so long.
そうだ ぼくにとって「正解」なんてどうだっていい
That's right, for me, what does a "correct answer" even matter?
この生が正しいか間違いか自分で決めるから
Whether this life is right or wrong, I'll decide for myself.
鏡に映った 僕の色は全部 僕のためにあったのに
All the colors of me reflected in the mirror were meant just for me,
気づいたらこの手を離れていた
but before I knew it, they slipped away from my hands.
名前も顔も隠したアノニマスに ぼくの何がわかるの？
What do anonymous people who hide their names and faces know about me?
輪郭さえぼやけそうな痛みを
From this pain that blurs even my outlines,
僕の全部 取り戻さなくちゃ
I have to take back all of me!
なんの騒音さえうるさいほどになる前に
Before the noise roaring as loud as a nuisance takes over completely
つまらないデイズもう散々ね！
Boring days are already over!
奇跡願っているだけの人生
A life where you're just wishing for miracles
watch me do, do-ru-do
呪術秘中トリック無しのマジック
Magic without any tricks or secrets
i wanna be free! だってまだふりだし
I wanna be free! Because I'm still at the starting line
(the party ain't started)
hey タクシー ちょっと 宇宙 迄
Hey taxi, take me to space for a bit
秒針は音を立てて夜を急かす魔王のように
The second hand, like a monster, ticks loudly, urging the night
人生は一瞬にして溶ける魔法
Life is a magic that melts away in an instant
それならば駆け抜けて想い通り！
If that's the case, then run through it as you wish!
おしゃまな馬車飛び乗って drivin'
Jump on the playful carriage and start drivin'
あたしは大変身 メイクアップ！
I'm in the middle of a great transformation, make-up!
我儘のままに燦爛に注意
Be careful not to get caught up in selfishness
洒落た街で dancin'
Dancing in a stylish city
左様ならグッバイ劣等感
If that's the case, goodbye inferiority complex
何時かは喝采クラップオウデエンス
Someday, applause from the audience
皆々御唱和あれ！
Everyone, join in!
bibbidi bobbidi boowa
bibbidi bobbidi boowa, yeah
混乱がっても仕方がない
Even if it's chaotic, there's no other way
ガラスシューズで踊る tonight
Dancing in glass shoes tonight
bibbidi bobbidi boowa
bibbidi bobbidi boowa, yeah
今夜に明日など無い
There's no tomorrow tonight
ならば自由に踊った者勝ちでしょ？
So, those who dance freely win, right?
da-da-da-dance! ラララホ
Dance! La la la li ho
どんな問題も解は一つ
Every problem has only one solution
白紙も正解も間違いも愛す
Love blank papers, correct answers, and mistakes
本当のあたしの理想
My true ideal
ah 何だか世界は限界の気がしてし
Ah, the world seems to have limits I can feel
oh ただただ安心じゃあ心配
Oh, just being safe is worrying
ah 今すぐ jumpin', jumpin' out
Ah, jumpin' out right now
chitty chitty bang bang chitty bang bang
唯々諾々に危機感抱く日々に
In days when I feel an urgent crisis
ぎりぎり爆発気味
Explosive feelings are at their limit
たった今発散してしまおうか
Should I let it all out now?
まだまだビ・イ・ビ・イ弾巧みに乱射
Still firing away skillfully
一発じゃあ撃ち足りないわ
One shot is not enough
ついに導き出した君にアンサー
Finally, I found the answer
灰に成る迄踊って居ようよ
Dance until it turns to ash
bibbidi bobbidi boowa
bibbidi bobbidi boowa, yeah
パッと弾けた感情に
In the burst of emotions
言い訳を並べて過ごした
I spent my time making excuses
葛藤も知らない街明かり
The city lights, oblivious to my struggles
君だけだって嘘をついた
I lied, saying it was only you
信じたくもないままで踊っている
Dancing unwillingly, not wanting to believe
示すために連ね続けた言葉
I kept stringing words together to show
見えないの 僕が 僕の この声が聴こえている?
Can you see me? Can you hear my voice?
Dancer in the dark
シルエット すらも透明で きっと
Even my silhouette is transparent
不格好だけれどでも
Clumsy, but still
せめて声を枯らそう 必死に縋っても
Let me at least strain my voice
ずうっと証明を
Always proving
ねえ GHOST みたいだ
Hey, I feel like a ghost
散々怨んだ明るさと
Resentment towards the brightness
意味有りげに伸びていく影
Shadows stretching meaningfully
淡々と過ぎた一粒の
A single tearful word
君の言葉で泣きたくなった
You said made me want to cry
大切にしたいものが零れていく
Things I want to cherish are slipping away
示すままに綴り続けたい言葉
I want to spell out as shown, the words
見えてるの 僕が 僕の この声が届いている?
Can you see me? Can you hear my voice?
Dancer in the dark
シルエット すらも透明で きっと不格好だけれどでも
Even my silhouette is transparent, clumsy, but still
だから叫んで足掻いてさ
So I scream, dragging my feet
裸足のままで走って
Running barefoot
ねえ 気づいて教えてよ 答えは
Hey, notice me, tell me the answer
こんな僕の心まで馬鹿にしないで
Don't make fun of even my heart
灰色 の 街 が 嘲 笑 っ て る
The gray city is mocking
足取りも重くなる
My steps become heavier
声を枯らして 叫んで 足掻いて
Straining my voice, screaming, struggling
裸足 で 走り 続 け て
Continuing to run barefoot
変わらないように
To stay the same
諦めないように
To not give up
連ね続けるだけだ
Just keep stringing together
見つけてよ 僕の 僕の この声が聴こえている?
Find me, can you hear my voice?
Dancer in the dark
シルエット すらも 透明で
Even my silhouette is transparent
きっと不格好だけれどでも
Clumsy, but still
せめて声 を 枯らそう
Let me at least strain my voice
必死 に 縋っ て も ずうっと 証明 を
Desperately hammering, always proving
ねえ GHOST みたいだ
Hey, I feel like a ghost
パッと弾けた感情に
In the burst of emotions
言い訳を並べて過ごした
I spent my time making excuses
葛藤も知らない街明かり
The city lights, oblivious to my struggles
君だけだって嘘をついた
I lied, saying it was only you
信じたくもないままで踊っている
Dancing unwillingly, not wanting to believe
示すために連ね続けた言葉
I kept stringing words together to show
見えないの僕が僕のこの声が聞こえている?
Can you see me? Can you hear my voice?
Dancer in the dark
シルエットすらも透明できっと不格好だけれど
Even my silhouette is transparent, clumsy, but still
せめて声を枯らそう必死に縋ってもずーーっと
Let me at least strain my voice, desperately hammering
証拠をねぇ ゴーストみたいだ
always proving, hey, I feel like a ghost
散々怨んだ明るさと意味ありげに伸びていく影
Resentment towards the brightness, shadows stretching meaningfully
淡々と過ぎた一粒の君の言葉で泣きたくなった
A single tearful word you said made me want to cry
大事にしたいものが零れていく
Things I want to cherish are slipping away
示すまに綴り続けたい言葉
I want to spell out as shown, the words
見えてるの僕が僕のこの声が届いている?
Can you see me? Can you hear my voice?
Dancer in the dark
シルエットすらも透明できっと不格好だけれど
Even my silhouette is transparent, clumsy, but still
空っぽのサイレン 乾いた施錠音
Empty siren, dry lock sound
ガラガラ スケーター 賑わえ 三点リーダー
Clattering skater, lively ellipsis
どんな言葉にもちゃんと綴りがあった
Every word had its proper spelling
もう何言わずに 遊ぼう
Let's play without saying anything more
どうでもいい朝に慣れ過ぎて
Getting too used to indifferent mornings
傘は持ってない 借りていた未来
I don't have an umbrella, borrowed future
返しきれず隠しきれず からから
Unable to return, unable to hide, clinking
街征く 余所者
Passersby, strangers
ねぇねぇ 独りだ 肩触れたのは
Hey, hey, I'm all alone, what brushed my shoulder
メイビー レイニー 君はとうとう居ないんだね
Maybe rainy, you're finally not here anymore
かなしむはないよ よろこぶもないよ
There's nothing to be sad about, nothing to be happy about
メイビー レイニー 好き勝手な茜色に
Maybe rainy, into the selfish madder red
減点方式の舗装路を染める
Dyeing the deduction-style paved road
レイニー レイニー こんな間違えたんだね
Rainy, rainy, we made such a mistake
塗り潰していく パノラマ
Painting over panorama
レイニー レイニー 君は何点だったの
Rainy, rainy, what score were you?
好き勝手な茜色の正午
Selfish madder red noon
無類なクラクション ああやって喚いて
Incomparable claxons, crying out like that
殴り合えたら それで良かった?
Would it have been fine if we punched each other?
泣いて 泣いて 泣いて 何が残った
Crying, crying, crying, what was left?
使い捨ての 今日を 余したくないな
I don't want to waste today
喧騒5分の 砂地公園 宇宙の裏
5-minute din, sandy park, back of the universe
白い煙に吹かれながら喋う
Chatting while blown by white smoke
救いのない 世迷言
Hopeless murmurings
ねぇねぇ 独りだ 頬伝ったのは
Hey, hey, I'm all alone, what ran down my cheek
メイビー レイニー 走馬灯みたいなキス
Maybe rainy, a kiss like a flash before my eyes
不確かな 声に 似ている 青に
To the blue resembling an uncertain voice
ほんの 僅かに 雨の 随に
Just slightly, at the mercy of the rain
君も征くなら 無事を祈っている
If you're also going, I'm praying for your safety
ほんの 僅かに 雨の 波間に
Just slightly, in the waves of the rain
君もゆくなら 道を祈っている
If you're also going, I'm praying for your path
ねぇねぇ 独りだ 肩触れたのは
Hey, hey, I'm all alone, what brushed my shoulder
メイビー レイニー 君はとうとう居ないんだね
Maybe rainy, you're finally not here anymore
かなしむはないよ よろこぶもないよ
There's nothing to be sad about, nothing to be happy about
メイビー レイニー 好き勝手な茜色に
Maybe rainy, into the selfish madder red
減点方式の舗装路を埋める
Filling the deduction-style paved road
レイニー レイニー これで良かったんだよね
Rainy, rainy, this was fine, right?
塗り潰していく パノラマ
Painting over panorama
はい！皆様ありがとうございました！
Yes! Thank you very much!
続いて3曲、私のオリジナルソング「Template」
Next, I performed three of my original songs—"Template",
「Ghost」「バイバイレイニー」を、ダンサーさん引き連れて歌って踊らせていただきました！
"Ghost", and "Bye Bye Rainy"—along with my dancers!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
いや、ダンサーさんがね、いるだけでもう華がね、添えられて、あの、とても助かりますと。
Having the dancers there just adds so much splendor, and it's a huge help.
えー、皆様本当にありがとうございました！ダンサーさんいつもありがとうございます！
Everyone, thank you truly so much! And thank you as always to the dancers!
はい、ということで、皆さんいかがだったでしょうか？喝采、ありがと！
Yes, so, how was it everyone? Thank you for the applause!
ちゃんとねコメント見えております、喝采ありがと。
I can see the comments properly, thank you for the applause.
お帰りスイちゃん、ありがとうございます！
"Welcome back, Suichan," thank you very much!
え、ということで、えー、次からはゲストパートなので、
So, um, starting next is the guest part,
ゲストが来ますよ。さて、ゲストは誰かな？誰かな？
so a guest is coming. Now, who could the guest be? Who could it be?
あの人だ！
It's that person!
次のステージへバイバイ！
Bye-bye to the next stage!
ハロー ハロー ハロー
Hello, hello, hello,
幕はもう開いてるんだずっと
The curtain has been open all along,
いま真空さえ揺らして響かせる
Resonating and shaking even the vacuum right now,
そんな音楽を！
Such music!
さあ
Now,
切り裂く静寂
Cutting through the silence,
全速前進
Full speed ahead,
生み出す引力で
With the gravitational pull we generate,
光速のパッセージ
A light-speed passage.
アレグロで今日も舞って
Dance today in allegro as well,
わななく轟音
A trembling roar.
The show must go on
消えない一拍を
Weaving more of
もっと紡いで
That unfading beat,
打ち鳴らし今日も万全で！
Resounding, fully prepared today!
描く放物線ずーっと煌めいていけるように
So that the drawn parabola can keep sparkling forever,
テンポ早めて最速で到達だ
Speed up the tempo and arrive at top speed!
進め一直線きっと君まで届くように
Advance in a straight line so it surely reaches you,
期待の声はもうすぐ
The voice of expectation is coming soon.
描く放物線ずーっと煌めいていけるように
So that the drawn parabola can keep sparkling forever,
テンポ早めて最速で到達だ
Speed up the tempo and arrive at top speed!
進め一直線きっと君まで届くような
Advance in a straight line so it surely reaches you,
音楽を
The music.
さあ
Now,
切り裂く静寂
Cutting through the silence,
全速前進
Full speed ahead,
生み出す引力で
With the gravitational pull we generate,
迎撃のハイトーン
An intercepting high tone,
大胆なシンコペーション
A bold syncopation,
揺らいだ衣装
Swaying costume.
The star of the show
新たな一拍を
Connecting more of
もっと繋いで
That new beat,
アレグロで今日も舞って yeah
Dance today in allegro yeah,
奏でよう今日のセクションを
Let's play today's section,
アレグロで今日も舞って
Dance today in allegro.
描く放物線ずーっと煌めいていけるように
So that the drawn parabola can keep sparkling forever,
テンポ早めて最速で到達だ
Speed up the tempo and arrive at top speed!
進め一直線きっと君まで届くように
Advance in a straight line so it surely reaches you,
期待の声はもっと遠くへ
The voice of expectation goes even further beyond,
刻みの声はもっと響いて
And the rhythm echoes even more.
描く放物線ずーっと煌めいていけるように
So that the drawn parabola can keep sparkling forever,
テンポ早めて最速で到達だ
Speed up the tempo and arrive at top speed!
進め一直線きっと君まで届くように
Advance in a straight line so it surely reaches you,
期待の声はもっと遠くへ
The voice of expectation goes even further beyond,
刻みの声を響かせて
Making the rhythm echo out.
さあ 全速前進
Now, full speed ahead
生み出す引力で
With the gravitational pull we generate,
迎撃のハイトーン
An intercepting high tone,
大一番のシンコペーション
A pivotal syncopation,
咲いた我心（がしん）セッション
A blooming ego-heart session,
揺らめいた衝動がオーバーヒート寸前
A flickering impulse on the verge of overheating,
新たな一歩を
Take a new step forward
もっと繋いで
And connect it even more.
アレグロで今日も待って
Waiting for you today in allegro as well,
奏でよう今日のセクションを
Let's play today's section.
語り合おう今日のセクションをさあ
Let's talk about today's session, now—
アレグロで今日も待って
Waiting for you today in allegro as well.
高速じゃ足りない…
Not fast enough...
もうすぐ迫ってる
Our rendezvous is fast approaching,
ランデブー
approaching,
もうフルスロットル向かってる
heading out at full throttle.
月が満ちるまで時間はもうない
There's no time left until the moon is full.
まだ君は待ってる
You're still waiting, I know,
わかってる
humming and smiling,
歌っては笑ってる 余裕なんかないくせに
even though you've got no room to spare.
光速じゃ足りない 足りない
Speed of light isn't enough, not enough!
切り取った starry night starry night
Carve out a starry, starry night.
逃げ切るよ 明日 明日
We'll outrun tomorrow, tomorrow,
君に見せたいから
because I want to show it to you.
夜はまだ明けない 明けない
The night isn't over yet, not yet,
夢はまだ覚めない 覚めない
the dream hasn't faded yet, not yet.
太陽のない方へ
Heading toward where there is no sun,
凹凸のハイウェイ 鳴らして
roaring down the uneven highway,
大きめの一歩で ワンサゲイン
taking a giant step, once again!
月が満ちるまであと 110 秒
110 seconds left until the moon is full.
今フルスロットル 向かってる
Heading out at full throttle now,
下を向かないように 走ってる
running so I won't look down.
悩んでる暇はない
There's no time to hesitate.
光速で巡り巡り 今度こそ make it make it
Circling at light speed, this time we'll make it, make it!
逃げ出そう 今夜 今夜
Let's slip away tonight, tonight,
君をさらってから
after sweeping you away.
夜はまだ明けない 明けない
The night isn't over yet, not yet,
夢はまだ覚めない 覚めない
the dream hasn't faded yet, not yet.
太陽のない方へ
Heading toward where there is no sun,
穹を駆け て
racing across the skies...
高速じゃ足りない
Light speed isn't enough.
未開の世界へ
To an uncharted world!
光速じゃ足りない 足りない
Light speed isn't enough, not enough!
到着だ moonlight moonlight
Arrival at moonlight, moonlight.
追い付いた 今日は 今日は
Caught up with it today, today,
君と見ていたいから
because I want to see it with you.
夜はまだ明けない 明けない
The night isn't over yet, not yet,
夢はまだ覚めない 覚めない
the dream hasn't faded yet, not yet.
太陽のない方で
In the place where there is no sun,
過ぎを越えて
passing beyond...
あの空で輝いた流星を追いかけて
Chasing the shooting star that shined in that sky,
いつか君を照らすから 彗星のスターライト
I'll illuminate you someday—the comet's starlight!
生まれたばかりの小さな光は
A tiny light, just born,
消えてしまいそうな声で
with a voice that seemed ready to fade,
歌を歌ったんだ
sang a song—
誰かに取っとくように
as if saving it for someone special,
遠くの声を張り絞って
straining her voice far into the distance.
今はまだ響かないけど
Though it doesn't resonate yet,
いつかこの街に
someday in this town...
満天の星を降らせよ
Let a sky full of stars fall down!
華々いほど煌めくよ 何もかも忘れるくらい
Glittering as brilliantly as fireworks, enough to make you forget everything,
飛び切りのステージを 歩ける 今夜は譲れない
walking onto the ultimate stage—tonight cannot be yielded!
夜はまだ明けない ほどに胸を躍らせて
The night isn't over yet, making my heart dance so much,
手を取って さあ行こう 彗星のスターライト
take my hand and let's go—the comet's starlight!
叶えたい願いを
The wish I want to make come true,
浮かべた光は
the floating light
ずっと出会いを待ってる
has been waiting to meet you all along.
早く見つけてよ
Hurry up and find it!
理図を描いただけじゃ
Just drawing out a blueprint
きっとまだ進めない
won't make us move forward yet.
踏み出したばかりだけど
Even though we've only just stepped out,
自らその心に
deep within your own heart,
真っ赤な花を咲かせよう
let's make a crimson flower bloom.
宇宙にしてみせるから
I'll turn it into a universe,
次元さえも超えるくらい飛び切りの踊り子を
an extraordinary dancer transcending even dimensions.
上げる声は覚めないで
Don't let the raising voice fade away,
一度きりの瞬間だって大事なの踏み出していく
even a once-in-a-lifetime moment is precious as we step forward.
彗星のスターマイン
A starmine of comets!
数えきれないほどの星がすれ違って
Countless stars passing each other by,
違う色で光っているんだ
shining in different colors.
その中ではたして
Within all of that,
何が残せるのかな きっと誰よりも青く
what can I possibly leave behind? Surely, an azure light
強い光を
stronger than anyone else's!
満天の星を降らせよう
Let's make a sky full of stars fall down,
眩いほど煌めくよ なにもかも忘れるくらい
glittering so dazzlingly, enough to forget everything,
飛び切りのステージを
an extraordinary stage!
満天の星を降らせよう
Let's make a sky full of stars fall down,
眩いほど煌めくよ なにもかも忘れるくらい
glittering so dazzlingly, enough to forget everything,
飛び切りのステージを
an extraordinary stage!
踊りにもねをうっつらさせて
Let your dancing sweep you away in a daze,
私のこと見ていてね彗星のスターマイン
and keep watching me: the comet's starmine!
アンチグラビティ・ガール
[Anti-Gravity Girl]
悲しんでいられそうなほどに西へ東へ
Heading east and west so much it's hard to even feel sad,
また迷子になって蹴飛ばして 風邪ひいて
getting lost again, kicking away, catching a cold,
探すよ今日もちょっとおかしな足下
searching today, too, at our somewhat strange feet.
銀河系のどこかで読み間違って
Misreading somewhere in the galaxy,
右に骨盤ねじ回して 指きって
twisting my pelvis to the right, crossing my fingers,
でたらめなねどんドスケッチもなくて
with not even a messy sketchbook,
それでも転ろびで空を飛んでみたい
yet still wanting to trip and fly through the sky—
思わず飛んでみたんだ
I tried flying on a whim!
いつかんだって 十万マイルまで見たことない
Whenever it is, to 100,000 miles, at a speed
スピードでキミも乗せて 宇宙なぐさめだってさ
I've never seen before, carrying you too—saying it's comfort for the universe,
今までの全部をこわしたい
I want to destroy everything up until now.
壊したい壊したい
I want to break it, I want to break it!
見られない夜だはばむワクワクしちゃうな
A night where you can't sleep, it's so thrilling!
鼻血が出そうなほど西へ東へ
Heading west and east till I'm about to get a nosebleed,
また迷子になって怪我して
getting lost and hurt again,
風邪ひいて探すよ 今日も
catching a cold, and searching today too.
ちょっとおかしな色をした
With a slightly strange-colored
ガラクタみたいな夢のパーツを
junk-like dream part,
虹色の工具で見よう見まねで
let's copy it using rainbow tools,
意味不明なネジを回して 指切って
turning random screws and cutting our fingers.
でたらめな理論でスケッチもなくて
With random theory and no sketch,
それでもこの船で空を飛んでみたいな
still, I want to fly through the sky in this ship.
思うまま飛んでみたいんだ
I want to fly just as I imagine,
いつか浮かんで宇宙まで
floating up into space someday,
見たことないスピードで
at an unprecedented speed,
君も乗せて
carrying you along too.
悠長な歌うたってさ
Singing a leisurely song,
今までのぜんぶを笑いたい
I want to laugh at everything until now.
見慣れない操作盤
An unfamiliar control panel,
ワクワクしちゃうな
makes me so excited!
まず意味もなくぜんぶ押して
First pressing everything for no reason,
間違えて倒れた機体
and making the machine collapse by mistake.
転んで夜空を見上げた
Falling down, I looked up at the night sky.
そろそろ時間だ
It's almost time,
準備はもうできてる
preparations are already complete.
彼方の彼方まで
To the far, far distance,
明日浮かんで宇宙まで
floating tomorrow up into space.
嘘みたいな本当を見つけたいの
I want to find a truth that seems like a lie,
ポンコツだって承知さ
knowing full well it's a piece of junk.
迷っても止まっていても笑っていたい
Whether lost or stopped, I want to keep smiling,
まるでファンタジー 素晴らしい日々だな
just like a fantasy, what wonderful days.
まだまだ探してたんだよ B級のドリーム
Still searching for a B-grade dream,
永遠にさ 今夜 浮かんで 宇宙 まで
floating into space tonight, forever.
まだ知らない場所まで
To a place we still don't know,
君も乗せて
carrying you along too.
重力なんて知らない
Knowing nothing of gravity,
ハリボテでもいい このまま
even if it's paper-mache, let's stay like this.
悠長な歌うたってさ
Singing a leisurely song,
これからのぜんぶも笑いたい
I want to laugh at everything from now on.
笑っていたい
I want to keep smiling,
I want to keep smiling.
笑ってたい！
I want to keep smiling!
イエーイ！どうもどうもどうも！
Yay! Hello, hello, hello!
お疲れ様でした！
Great job!
こんにちは！
Hello!
いやまさかの衣装に…
I mean, in this unexpected costume...
いやまさかの衣装で来ててもらいました！
you came wearing this unexpected costume!
こんにちは！起立気をつけて、月の美兎です、よろしくお願いします！イェーイ！
Hello! Attention, bow, I'm Tsukino Mito, nice to meet you! Yay!
いやもうね、今回衣裳をこうしてね、DJブースにお呼びしてDJをねして貰うことになったんですけど
Well, this time, we invited you to the DJ booth in this costume to DJ for us,
いやいやいや、いつもお世話になっております
and well, we're always in your care.
あ、なんか、あの、背景がね、面白い感じになってますね
Ah, somehow, um, the background has become quite an interesting sight.
走りたい感じ
It looks like you want to run.
走って…あ、ジャンプして…
Run... Ah, jump...
これがもうリハーサル時からずっと面白そうなんですよね
This has looked so hilarious ever since rehearsals.
これ絵面が良くて、絶対してほしいって
The visual is great, so we definitely wanted you to do it.
でね、このDJをね、あの、やってもらおうかなってなったときに、あの、アンダーグラウンドいてえなと思って
And you know, when we decided to have you DJ, I thought, "I want to be underground,"
歌うのはちょっと、決勝してえなと思って、急遽
and thought, "I want to sing, I want to retire," so abruptly...
初めて聞きまして、私だが歌うアンダーグラウンド
It's the first time I heard that I would sing "Underground."
そうかもな
That might be true.
緊張するじゃん
It's nerve-wracking, right?
しかも、めっちゃ難しい
Plus, it's super difficult.
難しいですよね
It is difficult, isn't it?
誰が悪いんだろう
Who's to blame?
あの、カメラのズームの仕方がおかしいですね、これ
Um, the camera zooming method is weird here.
だいたいアンダーグラウンドがある
Generally, there's "Underground."
まあ、それはしょうがない
Well, that can't be helped.
本当ですよ、感じてます
Really, I feel it.
私もステラステラとかね、あの、ミドグラで一緒になってるんですけど
I've also been together on Stellar Stellar, etc., in Mid-Gra,
大体あの、高難易度なんで
and it's generally high-difficulty.
いやですもんね、なんか恐ろしい回だな
It's awful, isn't it? What a terrifying episode.
吊り下げのタイガーが始まりましたからね
Because the hanging tiger has started.
はい、で、ここは、結構、あれですか、久しぶり…
Yes, and here, is it been quite a while...
一緒にステージで歌うのって、一応お祭りぐらい？
Singing together on stage, like at a festival?
そう、私も一方的に出したことはあって
Right, I've put things out unilaterally before,
私もある、そう、でも、やっぱ配信上で
I have too, yeah, but on stream,
一緒に並んだことはなかった
we've never stood side by side like this.
あまりない、初ではないけど
Not often, though not the first time.
初ではない、あの、Vカニっていうイベントで
Not the first time, at an event called Vkani,
一緒にね、あの、トーク…フジテレビ…そう、フジテレビ
together, um, talking... Fuji TV... right, Fuji TV
でトークをさせてもらったきり、あんまり喋ってもらってなくて
ever since we talked there, we haven't really talked much.
でモブめちゃめちゃ行きたかったんすよ。
Well, I wanted to go so badly!
いや、ギョクスト見たかったな
Man, I wanted to see Gyokust.
いやガチで、息できなくて、あの喋れないけどいっていいですかっていうおも
Seriously, I couldn't breathe, like "Can I speak even though I can't breathe?"
すごい空気になりますよね
That creates such an intense atmosphere, doesn't it?
あの男気を使って、今日は、おめでとうございますみたいな
Using that manliness to say, like, "Congratulations today!"
それもちょっと気になったな
That also made me a bit curious.
なんかミトちゃんなら許してくれるかなと思ったんです
I thought Mito-chan would forgive me.
委員長の配信っぽい感じ
It feels very much like the Chairman's stream.
ね、確かにそうですよね
Yeah, that's true, isn't it?
ここはどれくらいぶりなんですか?
How long has it been since you were here?
いや、多分2年ぶりじゃないかな
Yeah, probably about 2 years, I guess?
2年? 2年?
2 years? 2 years?
あのアルバムのリリースパーティーで
At that album release party...
なんかDJそれこそね
And the DJ, right?
え、ソワソワ? そんな前って
Huh, nervous? So long ago...
本当に2020年だったな、あれは
It really was 2020, back then.
え、そんときにアングラを流した
And at that time, you played "Underground".
流した流した、で委員長が「イエーイ」だけ
Played it, played it, and the Chairman just went "Yay!"
そう言ってね、あと言ってたかな、確か
Saying that, and she said something else too, I think.
であと踊りまくって
And then dancing like crazy...
踊ってたの? 息切れるぐらい
Were you dancing? To the point of running out of breath.
なんかアングラのオタクって言われてました、SNS上で
Someone called me an Underground otaku on SNS.
え、じゃあそれ以来会ってないんですか?
Oh, so you haven't met since then?
それ以来会ってない
Haven't met since then.
そうだと思う、多分
I think so, probably.
いや、その2000何年とかととといえば
Well, speaking of 2000-and-whatever...
すいせいちゃんは結構古参Vですよね?
Suisei-chan is quite an early-generation VTuber, right?
あ、そうなんです、実は2018年の3月デビューでございまして
Ah, that's right, actually I debuted in March 2018.
あの最初個人勢でね
Starting out as an independent...
私個人勢の時から知ってたから、すいせいちゃんを
I knew Suisei-chan since her independent days, so...
え、何で知るんですか?
Eh, how did you know about her?
何で知るんだろう
How did I know?
一体何
What on earth...
いやでもやっぱ歌だと思うんですけど
Well, but I guess it was her singing.
そうなんだ、ありがとうございます。私ももちろん知ってました
Is that so, thank you very much. Of course I knew her too.
赤ちゃんの拳、めっちゃ懐かしいの
Baby's fist, super nostalgic.
うん、洗濯機の上で配信してます、って 出た出た、から知ってる
Yeah, broadcasting on top of a washing machine, "Ah, right, I know from that."
だからね、その時代を思うとね
So, when thinking about those times...
ちゃんとね、こうやって歌えるって
Being able to sing like this properly...
確かに、うれしい!
True, I'm so happy!
よかったね、本当
I'm really glad.
そうそこにバックにいのたぐがいて
And in the background Inotagu was there.
まさかいのたぐもいるとは思わなかった
Never thought Inotagu would be there too.
おかしいうよねこの構図、バックいのたぐ、おおい
Isn't this composition funny, Inotagu in the back, hey.
すいせいさんの復活ライブにお礼が出ていいのかって話もありますけど
There's also the question of whether it's okay to thank Suisei-san's comeback live.
前のVカニにもあのヨッピーさん、うんさんのいらっしゃって
At the previous V-Con, Yoppy-san and Un-san were there.
毎回なんか実写の男性を挟んで喋ってるような感じが
It always feels like talking with a real-life man sandwiched in between.
実写の男性はいないといけないんだ
A real-life man has to be there.
すいませんね本当ね、いやでも見れてよかったなこの組み合わせ本当
Sorry about that, really. Well, but I'm glad I got to see this combination.
いやでも本当に楽しかった
Yeah, but it was really fun.
ヨッピーさんめちゃくちゃ好きなんですね歌わせてもらって本当にありがとうございました
You love Yoppy-san so much, thank you very much for letting me sing.
こちらこそありがとうございました、貴重なもん聞けたわ
Thank you very much too, I got to hear something precious.
めっちゃ歌うまい人のアングラ聴けて嬉しかった
I was so happy to hear "Underground" sung by someone who sings so well.
あ、じゃあ、あの三戸倉のシバで
Ah, then, at Mito-gura's Shiba...
三戸倉です
It's Mito-gura.
三戸倉、三戸倉です
Mito-gura, it's Mito-gura.
よろしくお願いします
Nice to meet you.
三戸倉も三戸倉も担当が
Mito-gura also has a person in charge...
伴奏、まさかのね
Accompanying, of all things.
よろしくお願いします。というわけで、今日は来てくれてありがとうございました!
Thank you for coming today!
ありがとうございました。いのうえさん、月のみとちゃんでした
Thank you very much. It was Inoue-san and Tsuki no Mito-chan.
またね、バイバーイ
See you again, bye-bye!
きちない言葉で 誰かを傷つけた
Using filthy words I hurt someone
無視するつもりが 真に受けタレバ
Thinking I'd ignore it, but taking it seriously instead
「何て」で、また傷付いた
"What if", and I got hurt again
大好きだったもの ちょっと嫌いに
I had a feeling that something I used to love
なりそうな気がしてさ
was about to become something I disliked
やりもしないくせ 出来ないくせ 偉そうにしやがんな
Without even trying, without even being able to do it, don't talk down to me!
なにやってもうまくいかない 脳内じゃ戦争だもんね 突っ立ってたって
Nothing's working out, it's a war inside my mind anyway, standing here like this
なにやってもうまくいかない
Nothing's working out
愛して、愛して
Love me, love me
なにやってもうまくいかない
Nothing's working out
第三次 “うっせぇわ” “低脳” 聞いたことあんぞ
A major incident, "Usseewa", "Teinou" - have you ever heard those?
なにやってもうまくいかない
Nothing's working out
はぁ
Haa
“ほら” “見て” “すごいでしょう!” が発端になり
"Look", "See", "Aren't I amazing!" became the starting point
インスピレーションオマージュが飛び交うフィールドで
In a field where inspirations and homage fly back and forth
淡々とオリジナリティだかなんだか模索してけって?
Just steadily search for originality or whatever, they say?
茨でバラバラな脳内です
My brain is a mess of thorny briars
何歳したかもわからないおこちゃまが評価されてんだどうかししてよなに
A toddler who doesn't even know how old they are is getting praised, how messed up is that
って、そっちのセリフよな
Well, that's what I should be saying to you
まぁいいから全部聞き流してくださいどうか
Anyway, please just listen and let it pass through, please
なにやってもうまくいかない 脳内じゃ戦争だもんね 突っ立ってたって
Nothing's working out, it's a war inside my mind anyway, standing here like this
なにやってもうまくいかない
Nothing's working out
愛して、愛して
Love me, love me
なにやってもうまくいかない
Nothing's working out
第三次 “うっせぇわ” “低脳” 聞いたことあんぞ
A major incident, "Usseewa", "Teinou" - have you ever heard those?
なにやってもうまくいかない
Nothing's working out
いやになっても戻りはしない
Even if I hate it, there's no turning back
どんどんなんか気づいてんだどうかししてだって
Gradually I'm realizing that things are messed up anyway
ってか端から戻れはしない
I mean, there's no turning back from the start
どうして、どうして
Why, why?
あとちょっとで乗れやしない
Just a little more and I couldn't get on board
乗客は満員だもんねじっとしてたって
The passengers are already full, so standing still won't help
なにやってもうまくいかない
Nothing's working out
はぁ〜
Haaa~
“そうか!” 気付いて傷付いてスローダウン
"I get it!" Realized, got hurt, and slowed down
あっという間に切断案虫はフルテンです
Before I knew it, anxiety and frustration reached their peak
ダンスダンスダンスダンス 踊れ踊れ
Dance, dance, dance, dance, and keep dancing
卍パーティぶっ壊して知らばっくれて作れ
Smash the banquet party and pretend you didn't know anything
一般ピピロペ行こうぜ電光石火で
Ordinary people, line up in a flash, with lightning speed
鉄板のネタもはや全公演分…は?
A classic routine, already full house and tongue-tied... huh?
恋のネタバレ 「別れ」っぽいな
Love's spoilers, sounds like a "breakup".
人生のネタバレ 「死ぬ」っぽいな
Life's spoilers, sounds like "death".
なにそれ意味深でかっこいいじゃん…
What's that, profound and cool...
それっぽい単語集で踊ってんだ 失敬
Dancing through a collection of such words, excuse me.
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる 風
Tu-tu-ru-tu-tu-ru style
ぽいじゃん ぽいじゃん
Sounds like it, sounds like it.
とぅ とぅる とぅ とぅ とぅる 風
Tu-tu-ru-tu-tu-ru style
なにをやってもうまくいかないな
Nothing ever goes right,
戦争なもんです だって
Because it's like a war, after all.
なにをやってもうまくいかないな
Nothing ever goes right,
愛して 愛してないで
Love me, don't just act like you love me.
なにをやってもうまくいかないな うっせぇわ
Nothing ever goes right, shut up.
第303号性は背中聞いたことはぞ
Sector 303, have you ever heard of it?
なにをやってもうまくいかないな
Nothing ever goes right,
先生は狂々なもんです 突っ張ってだって
The teacher is crazy, acting tough after all.
なにをやってもうまくいかないな
Nothing ever goes right,
愛して 愛さないで
Love me, don't love me.
なにをやってもうまくいかないな 心配してるふりしてんのもう痛いよ
Nothing ever goes right, pretending to worry is already painful.
なにをやってもうまくいかないな
Nothing ever goes right,
なにもやってないだけじゃない？
Aren't you just doing nothing at all?
見せて欲しい
I want you to show me,
夢の続きまで、世界。
To the continuation of the dream, world.
溺れてたの、海よりも深い、はじめまして
I was drowning in it, deeper than the ocean, nice to meet you.
追いかけて掴んだのは 残酷な二法
What I chased and caught was a cruel binary.
私は歩くわ 降り出した雨よ 止まないで、
I will walk. Oh rain that started falling, don't stop,
恋してたんだ、つぶれた声枯らして、
I was in love, straining my crushed voice,
愛してるって叫んだんだ
Crying out that I love you.
すれ違っていたの、世界。
We were passing each other by, world.
ねじまがっていた事実も心も塗りつぶしてさ
Painting over the twisted facts and heart,
無理わかっても、無理して笑って傷ついてしまうの
Even knowing it's impossible, I force a smile and get hurt.
涙とまらないのは足が痛い、痛いせいなんだ
The reason my tears won't stop is because my feet hurt so much.
落としたナイフ...
A dropped knife...
私にはもうつかえない
I can no longer use it,
こんな結末、いそ泡にでもなってしまえ！
Such an ending, I might as well turn into sea foam!
「言いわけ」が欲しかっただけのおうじさま
A prince who just wanted an "excuse",
きせきもこえも魔法のキスも必要なかった
Miracles, voices, and magic kisses weren't necessary.
しあわせそうな夢よ、きかないで、
A seemingly happy dream, please don't ask,
恋してたんだ
I was in love.
なきむしノイズなんて、泡にでもなってしまえ！
Crybaby noise, turn into sea foam!
わかったの、あたしはこの足で立たなくちゃ
I realized, I have to stand on these feet of mine.
恋も、いたみも、ぜんぶうけとめていたいから
Because I want to embrace all of both love and pain.
おもいよ、とどいてよ
My feelings, reach out.
ものがたりがおわるまえに
Before the story ends.
おもいよ、さあ「あいしています」と、さけぶんだ！
My feelings, now, shout out "I love you"!
言いわけが欲しかっただけなのを
All I wanted was an excuse,
王子様 奇跡も恋も魔法のキスも
Prince, miracles, love, and magic kisses too,
もう魔法のキスも必要なかったんだ
I no longer needed magic kisses either.
しあわせそうな夢よ、いえないで、
A seemingly happy dream, don't tell me,
焦りせかんだった 泣き虫ノイズなんて
It was impatience, crybaby noise,
終わりでもなってしまえしまいへ
Even if it ends, turn into nothingness.
わかったの 私はこの足で立たなくちゃ
I realized, I have to stand on these feet of mine.
恋も痛みも全部受け止めていたいから
Because I want to embrace all of both love and pain.
もういいよ 遠ざけてよ 物語が始まる前に
That's enough, push it away before the story begins.
もういいよ そう愛していますと叫んだから
That's enough, because I shouted that I love you.
もういいよ そう愛していますと叫んだ…
That's enough, I shouted that I love you...
見せて欲しい
I want you to show me,
夢の続きまで
To the continuation of the dream.
はじめまして
Nice to meet you.
愛された記憶もないのに
Though I have no memory of being loved,
愛されるぬくもりだけは知っていた
I only knew the warmth of being loved.
生まれてきたその瞬間から
From the very moment I was born,
誰かの手求めて生きてきたんだ
I've been living, searching for someone's hand.
ああ 伸ばしただけ崩れ落ちた
Ah, just reaching out, it crumbled away,
砂のようなこの想いが
this feeling like sand.
胸にあるうちはどこへも行けないんだ
While it's in my chest, I can't go anywhere.
終わらない夜には ひとりきりの朝には
In endless nights, in lonely mornings,
隣で笑えるように 涙がこぼれないように
so that you can smile beside me, so that tears won't fall,
孤独に輝いた ひとりぼっちの星が
a lonely, shining, solitary star
ここにいるよと叫んで歌になった
cried out "I'm here" and became a song.
誰かがそれを見て 綺麗と言った
Someone looked at that and called it beautiful.
虚しさと寂しさだけを持ち寄って
Bringing together only emptiness and loneliness
わけもなく泣きたくなるような
that make you want to cry for no reason,
火をつけてさ 温め合うんだ
lighting a fire and warming each other
もう二度とはぐれてしまわないように
so that we won't get separated ever again.
ねえ 正解とか間違いとか
Hey, whether it's right or wrong,
今は何もわからないけど
I don't understand anything right now,
ひとつだけ確かなのは 私がいるってことだけ
the only thing that's certain is that I exist.
近付いた分だけ 離れていく夢さえ
Even dreams that drift away the closer we get,
今ならその迷い事 笑える気がするから
now I feel like I can laugh at those hesitations.
孤独に輝いた 点と点を合わせて
Connecting the points that shone in the solitude,
ひとりじゃないと叫んで歌になった
cried out that I'm not alone and it became a song.
誰かがそれを見て 星座と言った
Someone looked at that and called it a constellation.
あなたの図上にも 今も降りかかる
Even now falling overhead upon you,
悲しみを溶かす 光になりたい
I want to be the light that melts away the sadness.
憂いも痛みも一緒に抱えていくから
Because I will hold your sorrows and pains together with me,
教えて
tell me.
終わらない夜には ひとりきりの朝には
In endless nights, in lonely mornings,
隣で笑えるように 涙がこぼれないように
so that you can smile beside me, so that tears won't fall,
孤独に輝いた ひとりぼっちの星が
a lonely, shining, solitary star
ここにいるよと叫んで歌になった
cried out "I'm here" and became a song.
いつか誰かの夜を 照らすように
So that it can someday illuminate someone's night...
照らせるように
So that it can illuminate...
終わらない夜には ひとりきりの朝には
In endless nights, in lonely mornings,
隣で笑えるように 涙がこぼれないように
so that you can smile beside me, so that tears won't fall,
孤独に輝いた ひとりぼっちの星が
a lonely, shining, solitary star
ここにいるよと叫んで歌になった
cried out "I'm here" and became a song.
誰かがそれを見て 綺麗と言った
Someone looked at that and called it beautiful.
虚しさと寂しさだけを持ち寄って
Bringing together only emptiness and loneliness
火をつけてさ 温め合うんだ
lighting a fire and warming each other
もう二度とはぐれてしまわないように
so that we won't get separated ever again.
おはようございますということで、え、
Good morning! So, uh,
カバーエリアがあって、アンドロメダを歌って、
we had the cover area, sang Andromeda,
もうなんかここてもう11曲ぐらい、もう10曲ぐらい歌ってるんですけれども、
and we've already sung about 11, or about 10 songs up to this point,
え、そろそろね、もう時間も時間ですので、あの、告知の方を皆さんにお伝えしたいと思います。
um, soon, since it's getting late, um, I'd like to share an announcement with everyone.
さあ、告知は何かな？何かな？
Now, what could the announcement be? What could it be?
VTRがあるそうです。どうぞ！
It looks like there's a VTR. Here it goes!
ということで、2023年1月25日、星街すいせい2ndアルバム『SPECTER』の発売が決定しました！イェーイ！
So, it has been decided that Hoshimachi Suisei's 2nd album 'SPECTER' will be released on January 25, 2023! Yay!
え、今年3月にリリースした『テンプレート』をはじめ、今回も超豪華な作家さんたちに、え、作曲をお願いいたしました。
Um, starting with 'Template' released in March this year, once again we asked super luxurious creators to compose music for us.
全11曲が収録される予定でございます。えっと、こっち、こっち、あ、こ、こっち。
It is scheduled to include a total of 11 songs. Um, this way, this way, ah, hi, this way.
ここです！こんな豪華作家陣です。
Here it is! These are the luxurious creators.
わあ、ありがとうございます！
Wow, thank you so much!
ちょっとね、あの『SPECTER』っていうのがまあどういう意味なのかは、あの、アルバムを聞いてみてね、あの、察していただければみたいな。
Um, as for what 'SPECTER' means, well, I hope you can listen to the album and figure it out.
ちょっとあの、かっこいい寄りの曲多めで、ロックっぽい曲を収めたアルバムになっておりますので、
It's an album featuring a lot of cool-leaning tracks and rock-style songs,
え、この後22時から各種CDショップやホロライブオフィシャルショップにて予約が開始されます。
so pre-orders will start at 22:00 tonight at various CD shops and the hololive official shop.
ぜひ予約してください。
Please make sure to pre-order.
よろしくお願いします！え、ちなみに先行予約者限定の店舗特典はこちら。
Thank you very much! Oh, and the store bonuses for early pre-order are right here.
いっぱいある。
There are so many.
見てね。言わない、見てね。
Take a look. I won't say it, just look.
はい、詳しくは概要欄やTwitterをチェックしてください。
Yes, please check the description box and Twitter for details.
はい、ということで、え、重大告知はアルバムでした！
Right, so, um, the major announcement was the album!
で、終わるかと思いきや、え、告知がまだたくさんあるって話なんで、もう1個ブイがあります。
And just when you thought it was over, um, since there are still lots of announcements, there's another VTR.
あ、どうぞ！
Ah, here it goes!
え、ハッシュタグは「＃きらきらすいせい」でつぶやいてください。
Um, please tweet using the hashtag '#KirakiraSuisei'.
え、ここ見づらいけどこれ、うわ、本当にありがとうございます！やっと2回目やることができました。ありがとうございます！
Um, it's hard to see here, but wow, thank you so much! We were finally able to hold the second one. Thank you!
いつもね、私があの運営さんにあの、お問合せをしてくれって言ってたんですけど、きっとたくさんお問合せをしたので、これができることに、
I always told you guys to contact management, and you must have sent tons of inquiries, which is why we're able to do this—
なったんでしょう。本当に皆さんありがとうございます！この気合を入れてね、あの準備頑張っておりますので、ぜひ、
must have happened. Thank you so much everyone! We're putting our full spirit into preparing for it, so please,
え、よろしくお願いします！また、今日3時にですね、株式会社ブシロードと見る箱byジョイサウンドさんが決定しました！ありがとうございます！
uh, look forward to it! Also, today at 3:00, Bushiroad Inc. and Miruhaco by JOYSOUND have been decided! Thank you!
え、続いて皆さんが気になるチケットのお知らせです。
Um, next is the ticket info you've all been wondering about.
え、現地会場チケットは指定席と学生割チケットを販売します。
Um, for venue tickets, we will sell reserved seats and student discount tickets.
受付期間は、え、今日この後ですね、え、22時から11月13日23時59分まで、ま、かなり短いのでね、あの、応募のご準備をどうぞよろしくお願いいたします。
The application period is from 22:00 tonight until November 13 at 23:59, which is quite short, so please prepare your applications.
また学生割引チケットはこの機械しか受け付けませんので、
Also, student discount tickets are only available through this machine,
学生の皆さんはですね、お得で手に入るこの機械をぜひ逃さぬようよろしくお願いいたします。
so all you students, please make sure you don't miss out on getting this great deal!
え、さらに配信チケットも販売しておりますので、え、チケット抽選外れた人とか遠方で来れないよっていう人はぜひこちらも買ってください。
Furthermore, streaming tickets are also on sale, so if you missed out on ticket lotteries or live too far away, please buy these as well.
え、詳しくは概要欄公演サイト、各販売サイトをチェックしてください。
For details, please check the description, event site, and sales sites.
いやあ、もりだくさんですね。
Man, that's a lot of announcements.
まさかアルバムとライブどっちも発表されるなんてみんな思わなかったでしょ。
I bet nobody expected both an album and a live tour to be announced!
そして、ここで、え、もう1回あります。
And right here... there's one more thing!
以前から情報が公開されていたねんどろいどフィギュアについて受注開始日が決定しました。
The pre-order start date has been decided for the Nendoroid figure previously announced.
こちら！
Here it is!
わあ、かわいい！
Wow, so cute!
なんか原型とかがね、あの、どっかのイベントで見れてたらしいんですけれどね。
Apparently prototypes were seen at some event before,
え、完成形はこのようになっております。
but the final version looks like this.
わあ、みんなが求めてたフィギュア、やっと出たよ。
Ah, the figure everyone wanted is finally out!
えっとね、マイクと、あの、斧と、あと、あの、四角いブロック4つを組み合わせた何かを持っています。
Let's see... she holds a microphone, an axe, and something combining four square blocks...
ぜひこちらもね、え、11月11日お昼の12時から予約開始となりますので、ぜひぜひチェックしてください。
Please check this out too! Pre-orders start November 11th at 12:00 PM, so be sure to check it out.
え、さらに今月はですね、え、復き早々ですが、
Furthermore, this month—right after my return—
11月20日20時からもう1回ね、あの、3D配信があるんですよ！
on November 20th at 8:00 PM, we're having another 3D stream!
何をするかと言いますと、え、仲のいいゲストとか呼んで、アルバムやライブの追加情報を公開する予定ですので、みなさんぜひ見に来てください！
As for what we'll be doing, we'll invite close friends as guests to reveal additional info about the album and live, so everyone please come watch!
11月20日。
November 20th.
ということでお、最後にアンコールとしてアルバムから新曲をお披露目しちゃいたいと思いますよ。
And with that, as an encore, I'd like to premiere a new song from the album!
今回お披露目する曲はなんと、作詞作曲を田淵智也さん、編曲を堀江晶太さんにお願いした楽曲です。
The song being premiered this time was written and composed by Tomoya Tabuchi, and arranged by Shota Horie.
このあと24時から、え、デジタル配信開始されて、え、この配信が終わったらMVも公開されますので、なんかはてなはてなてって動画があったと思うんですけど、それ、こちらもぜひご覧ください。
Starting at 24:00 today, digital distribution begins, and once this stream ends, the music video will also be released. There was a mystery video, so please check that out too!
かっこいい曲になってますので、ぜひ今から聞いてくださいね。それでは、聞いてください。
It's a cool song, so please listen to it starting now. Now then, take a listen.
セカンドアルバムから1曲おお届けします。灼熱にて純情。
Presenting a song from my second album: "Burning Purity".
What's純情？口に合いますか？
What's "Purity"? Does it suit your taste?
甘たるいだけじゃ満足しないね
Just being sweet isn't satisfying, right?
スタンバイはとっくにできての
The standby was ready long ago,
じゃタイムイズナウ タイムイズナウ
So time is now, time is now!
wii-wii-woo
メーデーメーデーこんな交信レッド
Mayday, Mayday, what a red communication—
浮気心おもしてても人間ばっか
Even if you play around, it's just humans.
つまいてタップしても体制影響なしのLonely
Even if you step and tap, it has no real effect, so lonely.
なあもっと知りたいのよさらっていくナイメー
Hey, I want to know more, sweep me away—
聞いたこともない爆音で
With an unprecedented blast of sound!
塵みたいな埃っぽいのも急いで壊してちょうだい
Hurry and smash even the dust-like specks.
不穏な声援よりもでかいのおくれ
Give me cheers louder than ominous ones!
私にステージをくれ
Give me the stage!
冷静冷静じゃなくて騒々しい方がいい
Instead of calm, a noisy atmosphere is better;
最高沸点にこだわりたいの 好きに埋もれたいんだ
I want to obsess over peak boiling point, to be buried in what I love.
独尊唯我なんて大様なこと言うないのって突き破ってできさしちゃって
Don't say grand things like "holier-than-thou"—smash through it and make it happen!
あーはは全然足りないくらいに燃やしたいんだって
Ahaha, I want to burn so intensely it's nowhere near enough!
狭い部屋の中だって無限に膨張していくんだろ
Even in a cramped room, it keeps expanding infinitely, right?
ボルテージ上げてくんだろ
Raising the voltage!
感情どうにもこうにも焦げる日々の不渡りに怯えるのも仕様がない
No matter what, being scared of unpaid days burning is inevitable.
知らないならどうしようかないならちょっと新しい道を切り開こうよ二人
If you don't know, what can you do? If not, let's carve a new path together!
世界中もっとバックフリップレル
Let's do more backflips across the world!
blablabla 歌るが、さるがベットして
Blah-blah-blah, singing like a monkey betting—
だけど負けるはずないな
But there's no way I'll lose!
救世主の采配は多分気まぐれ
The savior's arrangement is probably fickle.
じゃあどんな結果だって最高点にpassing
So whatever the result, passing to the highest point!
なあもっと知りたいのよ
Hey, I want to know more—
散々散らしてどうすんだ
What's the point of scattering it all over?
すがりついたって、めいたって、結局より戻すだけ
Clinging or lamenting, we just end up back where we started.
じゃあ最初から引き出しても怠いだけ
Then dragging it out from the start is just tedious.
満たして私の全身全霊を知れ
Satisfy me, know my whole heart and soul!
飽き足らない 見当たらないの 誰がカリスマ
Never satisfied, nowhere to be found—who's the charismatic one?
飽くなきすぎるアイズワイドシャット 見たぐさ 乱れとくさ
Too dazzling eyes wide shut, let's look messy and run wild.
妄想が全部正解にできそうじゃないか
Doesn't it seem like illusions can become all correct?
前例なんて全然ないけど 燃やしたいんだって
Even with no precedent at all, I want to burn it up!
形だけじゃなくってもう歴史になるんだ
Not just in shape, it's becoming history!
そこに立つ私に わわ、わわ、不可能なものなんてないの
To me standing right there—wa-wa, wa-wa, nothing is impossible!
感情が暴れ出すせいで 隅から隅まで笑われても知らないんだよ
Even if people laugh at me because my emotions run wild, I don't care!
鼓動のベースで払うのは続くから
The beating rhythm of my heart will continue, so let's go!
世界中のさ、口ずさみでも
Even if the whole world hums along—
燃えるほど、尽きるほど、ステージは熱くなる
The more it burns, the more it exhausts itself, the hotter the stage gets!
だからまだまだ振り絞れよ honey ちゃんと声は届くから
So squeeze out everything you've got, honey—your voice will surely reach!
狭い部屋の中で 心 無謀に
Burning my reckless heart in a narrow room...
どんなもんだいそうしてんだろ
What kind of mindset am I in?
リミット外してブーストして
Removing the limit and boosting up,
いっそ燃やし尽くしちゃえば
If I'm just going to burn it all down,
形だけなくなって歴史になるんだ
My physical form vanishes into history!
そこに立つ私に 往々
To me standing right there, oh oh,
不可能をも凌駕しちゃう情熱なんだよ
It's a passion surpassing the impossible!
それが正解なんだ
That's the correct answer!
適当な理由で口挟むなよ
Don't butt in with casual excuses.
知らないならちょっと黙るか？道を開けろよ
If you don't know, shut up and make way!
燃やし尽くして
Burning it all down,
灼熱にて純情
Pure passion in the scorching heat!